字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
下次你决定释放我朋友内心的冰霜恶魔时
Next time you decide to release my friend's inner ice demon,
能选在七月的某个时候吗
you do it sometime in July.
我只是想救她  西斯科
I was trying to save her life, Cisco.
我成为冰霜杀手时
When I became Killer Frost,
萨维塔出现在我面前  给我指明方向
Savitar appeared to me and showed me the way.
如果我们需要阻止萨维塔和拯救你的答案
If the answers that we need to stop Savitar
存在于未来  那我就需要去那里
and save you are in the future, then that's where I need to go.
你把萨维塔困在了神速力中
You trapped Savitar in the Speed Force.
告诉我你是怎么办到的
Just tell me how you did it.
-有人帮我  -谁帮你的
- I had help. - Help from who?
一个物理学家  她叫特蕾西·布兰德
A physicist. Her name's Tracy Brand.
我知道你是谁了
I know who you are.
闪电侠
第三季
第二十集
十六小时前
塞西尔
Cecile?
多数人到这时候
Most people quit...
就放弃他们的新年愿望了
their New Year's resolutions by now.
中城马拉松还有两个月
Central City Marathon is in two months,
我还要再减去
and I gotta shave--ooh!
我还要再缩短半分钟
I still got half a minute I gotta take off my time.
-你呢  -远不止半分钟
- You? - A lot more than 30 seconds.
我会在马拉松终点处
Look, I am going to wait for you...
等着你的
at the end of the marathon.
不行  你不能退出
No, you're not pulling out of this thing.
跟家里其他人相比
I am not as easy with running
我不怎么擅长跑步
as some other members of my family.
我就放过你吧  饶了你
I'm gonna let it slide. I'm gonna let it.
-是吗  -是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
你生气了吗
Are you getting mad?
我绝不会生气
I would never get mad.
我太爱你了  不会生你的气
I love you too much to be mad.
这个  我
That, I,
-我不是那个意思  -没事的
- I didn't really mean to-- - No, absolutely--
我看着你
I was looking at you,
顺嘴说出来了  我不想让你
and then it just came out, and I didn't want you
-觉得别扭  -抱歉  等一下
- to feel uncomfortable or-- - I'm sorry. Hold on.
-对不起  我得接一下  -没事  接吧
- Sorry. I gotta take this. - Yeah, yeah, yeah. Go for it.
什么事  好的  我马上到
Yeah? Okay. I'm on my way.
好的
Yeah.
不好意思
All right, sorry.
我得走了
I gotta head out.
她叫特蕾西·布兰德
Her name is Tracy Brand.
她是世界顶尖的理论物理学家之一
She's one of the world's top theoretical physicists--
至少她以后会是的
you know, or at least she will be.
说真的  她遵纪守法
No kidding. Girl Scout earns her merit badges.
获得2021年诺贝尔奖  科普利奖章
2021 Nobel Prize, Copley Medal,
总统赞扬
presidential commendation.
她是个天才  可对我们有什么用呢
She's a genius, but what's that to us?
她是阻止萨维塔的关键
She's the key to stopping Savitar.
未来的我说四年后
Future me said that four years from now,
布兰德博士发明了一种技术
Dr. Brand invents the technology
可以把萨维塔困在神速力中
that traps Savitar in the Speed Force.
-四年后就晚了  -对  但如果她那时
- Four years too late. - Yeah, but if she invents
发明了那项技术  那现在可能在研究原型机
the tech then, then maybe she's working on the prototype now.
非常正确  所以我们应该找到她
That's exactly right, so we should find her.
同意
Agreed.
抱歉
Sorry.
我们为什么又不去找凯特琳了
Why are we not looking for Caitlin again?
别激动  罗密欧和朱丽叶
Easy, Romeo and Juliet.
我们都没有忘记凯特琳
None of us have forgotten about Caitlin.
好  可未来的闪电侠已经确认了
Right, but future Flash already confirmed
她跟萨维塔结成了同盟
that she teams up with Savitar.
我们应该尽一切努力
We should be doing everything in our power
-阻止这件事发生  -我们知道
- to stop that from happening. - We know.
是的  那沃利去地球三
Right, so what is Wally doing
找他女朋友干什么
swanning off to Earth-3 to be with his girlfriend?
他应该在这里帮忙找到她
He could be here right now looking for her.
大家好像什么都没做
It's like no one's doing a thing.
大家什么都没做
No one's doing a thing?
巴里和沃利已经搜了整座城市六次
Barry and Wally searched the city half a dozen times.
大家什么都没做
No one's doing a thing?
每次一有机会  我就试着用震波定位她
Every chance I get, I try to vibe where she is.
我们在用面部识别技术
We're using facial recognition technology.
在用超能力提醒宝  在用卫星
We're using the meta-human app, the satellite.
我们在用所有的办法
We're doing everything we can.
我只是想把她找回来
I just want her back, okay?
如果你这么想她回来
Yeah, well, if you wanted her here so badly,
也许你就不该扯掉她的项链
maybe you shouldn't have ripped off that necklace
-把她变成了杀手  -好了
- and turned her into a killer. - Okay, okay.
-好了  -说说而已
- All right. - Just saying.
有发现了
We got a hit.
特蕾西·布兰德
Tracy Brand,
目前在念中城大学的理论物理课程
currently enrolled in CCU's theoretical Physics program.
我们打败邪恶极速之神的希望
So our hopes of defeating an evil speed god hinge
-取决于一名研究生  -没错
- on a grad student? - Yup.
可能更糟  BA和西斯科  我们开始吧
Could be worse. B.A., Cisco, let's do this.
走吧
Let's go.
散发着学术的吸魂荧光
Ahh, the soul-sucking fluorescence of academia.
虽说很激动人心
Yeah, this is exciting, though.
就像跟还未成为爱因斯坦的诺伯特相遇
It's like meeting Norbert before he was Einstein.
-阿尔伯特  -诺伯特  还是阿尔伯特
- Albert. - Norbert Albert?
你们闻到了吗
Do you guys smell that?
在烤东西吗
Toast?
我了个...
Holy--
你们干什么
What are you doing?
拯救你不被火痛苦地烧死吗
You mean save you from a painful, fiery death?
一切在我掌控中
I had it under control.
-少来了  -不如这样
- Come on! - Okay! You know what?
趁你的眉毛还在
Let's put this down
赶紧把这放下
while you still have your eyebrows.
你是故意放火的吗
Did you set the fire on purpose?
是的  我要把东西都烧掉
Yes, I'm burning everything.
-什... -什么
- W-- ev... - What?
-所有东西  什么  -我的研究
- Everything? What-- - My work.
我不知道为什么叫做研究
Well, I don't know why they call it "Work,"
因为全都研究无果
because none of it works.
这和我想的完全不一样
This isn't exactly what I expected.
-我也是  -布兰德博士
- Me neither. - Um, Dr. Brand?
叫我特蕾西就好了
Oh, no. Just Tracy.
我的论文失败了
I failed my dissertation.
十年努力付诸东流
Nothing like ten years down the drain
还欠了一屁股债
and a pile of debt as a legacy.
特蕾西  我们只是希望
Tracy, uh, w-w-we were just hoping
你能有空跟我们聊聊
that you'd have a moment to talk.
不行  我的汽车五分钟后就开了
Oh, no. My bus leaves in five minutes.
请告诉我  我没烧掉汽车票
Oh, please tell me I didn't burn my bus ticket.
太烫了
Yeah, that's hot.
汽车  你要去哪
Your bus? Where-- where are you going?
去大贝利汉堡店  我听说他们在招人
Big Belly Burger. I hear they're hiring.
什么  你说真的...
What? You're seri--
那你的研究呢
Well, what about all your research?
你是说我对异次元能量
You mean my "Unsubstantiated and transactional" inquiry
"完全虚假"的特性的毫无根据
into the "Purely suppositional" nature
又事务性的探索吗
of extra-dimensional energy?
-是吧  -是吧
- Yes? - Yeah?
浪费时间  或是正如赫什博士所说
A waste of time, or, as Dr. Hersh puts it,
"简直是滥用大学资源"
"A total misapplication of the university's resources."
我还不如开始练习
I might as well start practicing,
"你要加份薯条吗"
"Do you want fries with that?"
-要  -不是
- Yes. - No.
-BA  -别说了
- B.A. - Stop.
别因否定者而意志消沉
Look, don't let the naysayers get you down.
怀疑是我们的敌人
Your doubts, they're traitors.
别相信他们的话
Don't believe them.
你很聪明  去做手指薯条太大材小用了
Your mind is too fine to waste turning tubers into finger chips.
手指薯条
Finger... chips?
手指薯条就像是...
Finger chips. There's, like, a--
-他不是本地人  -别说了
- He's from out of town. - Stop.
你看你看  你不能放弃
Look, look, look. You can't give up.
你研究的相对论量子力学
Your work on relativistic quantum mechanics
及其在层际空间的应用理论
and its application to interspatial theory
在亚原子层面操作物质
to manipulate matter on a subatomic level,
是具有突破性的
it's groundbreaking.
我还没有和任何人说过这个假设
I haven't shared that hypothesis with anyone,
除了我的理疗师
other than my therapist.
-你是谁  -我们就是理疗师
- Who are you? - We're therapists.
是的
Yeah.
进来这里可真容易
Admission here is so easy.
把她带走  快
Get her out of here. Go.
那么
So...
你已经完全变成冰霜杀手了啊
you've gone full-on Killer Frost, huh?
新装扮  全是新的
New threads and everything.
我可不再穿铅笔裙了
No more pencil skirts for me.
我不想伤害你
I don't want to hurt you.
你休想
You won't.
但我会伤害她的
But I will hurt her.
西斯科
Cisco! Hey!
-你还好吧  -还好
- Hey, you good? - Yeah.
-这肯定会留疤了  -快来  快来
- That's gonna leave a mark. - Come on, come on.
-凯瑟琳在追杀特蕾西  -是的
- Caitlin's after Tracy. - Yeah.
这说明她在为萨维塔办事
That means she's working with Savitar.
中城警局
绝对是她  警探
That's definitely her, Detective.
冰冷的眼睛什么的
Icy eyes and all.
对  就是她
Yup, that's her.
我会把这个散布出去
So I'm gonna spread this around
这样大家就知道要注意她了
so everyone knows to look for her.
能稍等一会儿吗
Uh, can you give me one second?
如果凯瑟琳想要特蕾西死
Uh, so if Caitlin wants Tracy dead,
那我想你在未来看到的是真的
I guess what you saw in the future was true
她与萨维塔组队了
and she's teamed up with Savitar.
我只是没想到会这么快
I just didn't think it was gonna happen this soon.
真是让事情变得更复杂了
It certainly makes things more complicated.
让什么变得更复杂了
Makes what more complicated?
有超能力者袭击了中城大学
T-there was a meta attack at CCU,
但是我们没有什么线索
and we just don't have much to go off of.
真的吗  那可是大学校园
Really? It's a college campus.
-没人拍下来吗  -没有
- Isn't there video footage? - Uh, no.
都被消除了
It got...erased.
我肯定你们会弄明白的
Uh, well, I'm sure you two will figure it out.
乔  我能不能...
Joe, can I, um...
今早的事我感觉有点奇怪
So I'm feeling weird about this morning.
听着  当我和你说
Uh... Look, when I told you
我爱过你时  我不是想给你压力
that I loved you, I-I didn't mean to make you feel pressured.
不不不  我没感觉到压力
No, no, no, no, I-I didn't feel pressured.
好吧  那么  我们没事吧
Okay. So...we're good?
-完全没事  -那就好
- We're great. - Great. Okay.
既然这样
Um, in that case, uh...
祝你能抓到你的超能力者
good luck with your meta.
我刚才都听到了
Um, so I totally heard that.
-你想谈谈吗  -不
- Do you want to talk? - No.
你要去哪
Hey, where are you going?
最近的汽车站
Oh, uh, nearest bus stop.
不行  你应该待在这
Uh, no, you should stay here,
跟韦斯特警探待一会儿
um, with Detective West for a little bit.
为什么  那个速写家简直就是米开朗基罗
Why? That sketch artist was like freaking Michelangelo.
-你已经找到那女的了  -还没有
- I mean, you've got your woman. - Not yet.
在那之前  你可能会遇到很大危险
And until we do, you could be in a lot of danger.
[用以形容冰霜]
你真的认为杰克冻人的妹妹想杀我吗
You really think Jack Frost's sister wants to kill me?
-我谁都不是  -根据我的经验
- I'm no one. - In my experience,
她追杀你一次  她就可能还会追杀第二次
if she's come after you once, she's likely to do it again.
你看  这些所谓的目击证人过度保护
Look, this whole witness overprotection thing
是完全没有必要的
is totally unnecessary.
这只是次随机袭击
It was just a random attack.
汽车来了
The bus is coming.
我要走了
I gotta go.
我们得看着她
We need to keep an eye on her.
是啊
Yeah, we do.
她跑了
She got away.
我告诉你了她会去哪
I told you exactly where she'd be.
我到的时候巴里和西斯科在
Barry and Cisco were there when I arrived.
我说过他们会在的
As I told you they would be.
或许你心里所存在的凯特琳·斯诺
Maybe there's more Caitlin Snow inside you
比你让我以为的多
than you led me to believe.
你的意思是我故意让她走的吗
Are you saying I let her go on purpose?
是这样的吗
Did you?
你叫自己冰霜杀手
You call yourself Killer Frost,
但你还没杀过一个人
but you haven't actually killed anyone yet.
你我都可以成为神
You and I can both be Gods,
远离人类的伤痛和苦难
free of the pain and suffering of man.
你要做的
All you have to do...
就是杀了那个女孩
is kill the girl.
好吧  我没带现金
Okay. Look, I might not have any cash.
但是我有吉特斯的卡
But I have one of those, um, Jitters cards
上面集了十个章了
that has ten stamps on it,
所以你欠我一杯免费饮料
which means you owe me a free drink.
好吗
Okay?
请允许我帮助一个落难少女
Allow moi to help out a damsel in distress.
我来付我和这位女士的钱
I will pay for myself and the lady.
我要三重无奶油摩卡闪电侠咖啡
I will have a triple-shot, no-whip mocha Flash,
这位女士想点什么都可以
and anything this young lady desires.
我要冷静一下  我要一杯极速咖啡
Yeah, I, um--I need to calm down, so a Zoom.
极速咖啡
A Zoom?
没听说过
Never heard of it.
-是在秘密菜单上的  -秘密菜单
- Oh, it's on the secret menu. - Secret menu?
三重意式浓缩加一点红辣椒
Triple espresso with a shot of cayenne.
爱死了
Marry me.
等等  你今天早上在学院里
Hey, wait. You were at the college this morning.
不  今天早上吗  对啊
No--oh, this morning? Oh, yeah.
我现在想起你来了
No, I remember you now.
对  我在的  我叫HR
Yes, I was. H.R.
等等  你们是怎么回事
Wait, what is it with you people?
中城警局派你来找我的吗
Did the CCPD send you to find me?
不不  我来这里是因为
No, no, no, no. The reason I'm here is...
-我和我的团队对你的研究很感兴趣  -是吗
- my team and I are very interested in your research. - Really?
-是的  -你对我的量力力学理论感兴趣吗
- Yes. - You're interested in my theories on quantum mechanics?
你对波粒二象性的看法
Your ideas of wave-particle duality,
能量量子化
your quantization of energy,
量子理论中你的
and your time-symmetric formulation
-时间对称公式  还有  -边界条件如何
- of quantum theory and... - How the boundary conditions
导致了因果关系原则
lead to principle causality
以及心理学时间箭头
and the psychological arrow of time.
And the psychological arrow of time.
你还真懂不少
You really know your stuff.
吾粉  聪明
Well, je suis... smart.
别拽法语了  也别即兴发挥了
Lay off the French, and lay off the improv too, please.
让她不断说话就行
Just keep her talking.
谢谢你  米莎
Ah. Thank you, Mischa.
请  极速咖啡
Please. The Zoom.
-谢谢你  -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
来喝吧
Let's zoom.
伙计  是我多心吗
Mate, was it just me,
听起来像是HR想撩她
or did it sound like H.R. was trying to flirt?
没注意
Didn't notice.
今天中城警局的安全监控录像
Listen, the, uh, security footage today from CCU,
我们为了保护凯特琳的身份抹掉的那一段
the stuff that we wiped to protect Caitlin's identity?
我看了
I-I saw it.
我看到你们两个对打
As in, I-I saw the two of you squaring off.
好吧
Okay.
从我的角度来看
Well, from the angle that I saw,
看起来你当时完全能打中
it looked like you had a pretty clear shot.
好吧
Okay.
你当时可以打中她  西斯科  但你没有
You had a clear shot, Cisco, and you didn't take it.
-为什么  -朱利安  我在努力集中精神
- Why? - Julian, I'm trying to focus
只关注该关注的地方  我建议你也这样做
on what we're here to focus on. I suggest you do the same.
先生们  怎么样了
Gents, how we doing?
一切正常
Uh, all good.
这一次我不确定  巴仔
I don't know about this one, Bar.
HR其实不是我们最好的后援
H.R. isn't exactly our best closer.
他会搞定的
Ah, he'll be fine.
-你还好吗  -还好
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
-只是...  -塞西尔吗
- Just... - Cecile?
她让我措手不及
She's just-- she caught me off guard.
只是觉得我们还没到那一步
Just didn't think we were there yet.
很明显对于她而言到了
Well, obviously she is.
-那你呢  -我很在意她
- Are you? - I-I care for her a lot.
只是现在爱瑞丝  萨维塔
It's just with everything going on with Iris and Savitar
还有凯特琳那些事  我觉得我...
and now Caitlin, I just feel like I...
一直在对塞西尔隐瞒
lie to Cecile all the time.
那你可能就该停下
Then maybe you should stop.
你得找个时机告诉她关于沃利
You're gonna have to tell her about Wally
我  还有这一切  对不对
and me and all this at some point, right?
所以不如现在告诉她
So why not now?
你得知道
Well, just so you know,
你不该为了保护我们而对她有所隐瞒
you don't have to keep her in the dark for us.
如果你爱她  就该与她坦诚相待
If you love her, you should be honest with her.
至少你也是这么告诉我的
At least that's what you'd tell me to do.
那么...
Okay, so...
在大学里我一直没法
Here's the thing that I could never get them to understand
让他们理解  看...
at the university. See...
我一直在研究极速者
I've been studying speedsters.
你知道他们奔跑的时候
And so you know how, when they run,
是如何在身后产生一串闪电的吗
they generate a trail of lightning behind them?
光电效应
Light--lightning.
我并不认为完全是因为奔跑而产生的
I don't think all of that is generated by them running.
-我觉得...  -不是吗
- I think... - No?
有一部分是从别处而来
Some of it comes from somewhere.
就像是某种
Like, it's some sort of a--
就像是
like a--hmm.
神速力吗
Speed Force?
对  等等
Yeah. Wait.
-这个词用得好  -好吧
- That is a great term for it. - Well...
-神速力  -谢谢
- Speed Force. - Thanks.
所以我可以做一些计算
Anyway, so I've been doing some calculations.
我觉得可能有方式可以去操控它
I think there might be a way to manipulate it.
也许甚至可以控制它
Maybe even...control it.
也许甚至可以让它变成一个监狱
Maybe even turn it into a prison.
也许  是可以
Maybe. Um, yeah.
对对  突然想到而已
Yeah, yeah. I mean... Just a random thought.
你觉得一个人怎样可以实现这些
How do you think one would accomplish that?
-我不知道...  -没事
- See, I don't know... - Okay.
因为学校不给我的研究提供资金
Because the university wouldn't fund my research.
你为什么对这个那么感兴趣
Why are you so interested in this?
因为大家都觉得我疯了
Because everybody thinks I'm a crackpot.
显然我不这么认为
I certainly don't think you're a crackpot.
我
I--
怎么了
What's wrong?
-我们得走了  -等等  什么
- We should go. - Wait. What?
我们该走了  对
I think we should go. Yup.
大伙们  快来帮忙
Guys, guys, we need a little help here!
我们有麻烦了
We got a little trouble here!
闪电侠
Flash?
她在哪儿
Where is she?
在这里
Right here!
-又是她吗  -凯特琳  凯特琳  住手
- Her again? - Caitlin! Caitlin, stop!
-把她带走  -什么  什么
- Get her out of here! - What? What?
我和你有什么仇啊
What did I ever do to you?
这算什么  你现在是萨维塔的侍从了吗
So what? You're Savitar's lackey now?
统治地狱什么的可有趣多了
More fun to reign in hell and all that.
我会去让她沿着这儿折回来
All right, I'm gonna get her to head back this way.
她回来的时候  你击晕她  好吗
When she does, you gotta knock her out, okay?
-好吗  -好的
- Okay? - Yeah.
就现在  西斯科
Now, Cisco!
萨维塔说我不能杀你
Savitar says I'm not allowed to kill you,
但我不能让你跟着我
but I can't have you following me around.
上次是左腿  对吗
It was the left leg last time, right?
对
Right.
伤疤组织比一般组织更敏感
Scar tissue's a lot more sensitive than regular tissue.
这不是你
This isn't you!
现在是了
It is now.
凯特  凯特
Cait! Cait!
这就是闪电侠的基地吗
This is where the Flashy Flash goes down?
和我想象的不太一样  但很酷
It's not exactly what I imagined, but it's cool.
我一直好奇你怎么防止摩擦
So I always wondered how you kept the friction
积累到致命剂量的静电荷
from building up a lethal dose of static charge.
是硫化过得聚四氟乙烯
Yeah, that's vulcanized Teflon.
可以中和任何电荷不平衡
It neutralizes any electron imbalance.
好吧  那个白女巫
Okay, and the-- the White Witch?
我猜你知道她为什么追我
I'm guessing you know why she's after me.
她和一个来自未来的
Well, she's teamed up
邪恶极速者联手了
with an evil speedster from the future,
显然你研制出的技术把他困在了
and apparently you developed the technology to trap him
永恒之中  所以...
for an eternity, so...
你没开玩笑吧
You can't be serious.
绝对没有
Totally serious.
邪恶极速者
An evil speedster?
他叫自己萨维塔
He calls himself Savitar.
萨维塔  而且他来自未来
Savitar? And he's from the future?
-是的  -而我给他造了个陷阱
- Yup. - And I build a trap for him?
-我吗  -是你
- Me? - You.
在你造出之前他想杀了你
He wants to kill you before you build it.
所以他才派冰霜杀手找你
That's why he's sending Killer Frost after you.
冰霜杀手  她叫冰霜杀手
Killer Frost? Her name...is Killer Frost?
-是的  -我们知道一下子很难接受
- Yeah. - We know it's a lot to take in.
实话说  你们是在告诉我
Well, to be fair, you're basically telling me
我是《终结者》里面的莎拉·康纳
I'm Sarah Connor in "Terminator."
-这个...  -更像是
- Well... - Uh, more like...
-迈尔斯·戴森  -是的
- Miles Dyson. - Yeah,
-但做得是好事  -等等
- but good effort, though. - So wait.
你是在说  我那个关于
You're telling me my ideas about the, um...
神速力
The Speed Force.
神速力的猜想  可以控制  操纵  所有这一切
Speed Force, being able to control it, manipulate it, all of that...
是对的
I'm right?
看起来是
It appears so.
这是我
That's me?
诺贝尔奖
Nobel Prize?
全部这些
All of that?
在未来  是的
In the future, yeah.
特蕾西
Look, Tracy.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
我们需要你现在造出陷阱
We need you to build this trap now.
如果我造不出陷阱会怎么样
What happens if I don't build the trap?
一个对我们很重要的人会死
Someone very important to us is going to die.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
我知道
Uh, I know that, uh,
通常你们中一个会出去谈谈  但是...
normally one of you fellas goes out for the chat, but, uh...
这个归我
I got this one.
特蕾西
Tracy!
Oh, Tracy!
我在忙
I'm working.
我知道
I can see.
我想告诉你
I thought you'd like to be informed
HR在劝说特蕾西
that H.R. Has managed to talk Tracy around.
很好  这意味着我们可以开工了
Ah, perfect. That means we can get to work.
是的  首先我想知道一件事
Yeah, there's one thing I need to know first.
早些时候在吉特斯咖啡店外面
Outside Jitters earlier,
你本可以用震波阻止凯特琳
you could've stopped Caitlin with a vibe.
但是像中城大学一样  你没有
But just like CCU, you didn't.
我可不想跟你再废话一遍了
I'm not doing this again.
不行  不行
No, no, no, no, no.
你必须要
You are.
我要知道  西斯科
I need to know, Cisco.
告诉我你为什么做不到
Tell me why you couldn't do it.
给我让开
Get out of my way.
凯特琳现在本可以回家了
Caitlin could be home now.
你如果阻止了她  她现在就在这里了
Had you stopped her, she would be here.
但你没有  你没做到
But you didn't! You couldn't!
告诉我为什么
Tell me why!
因为我害怕
Because I'm afraid!
-害怕什么  -害怕会杀了她
- Afraid of what? - Afraid of killing her!
我带着两发上了膛的枪走来走去
I'm walking around with two loaded guns here,
随时都可能开枪
ready to go off.
她要是伤害了巴里  乔或者你
What if she's hurting Barry or Joe or you
而我必须得救你们  但无法控制我的能力
and I have to save you and I can't control my powers
最终杀死了她怎么办
and I end up killing her?
她是我最好的朋友
She's my best friend.
我宁愿死的是我
And I'd rather it be me than her.
特蕾西怎么样了
How's Tracy holding up?
还在观察
Ah, we'll see.
你告诉塞西尔我们的事了吗
Have you told Cecile about us yet?
塞西尔现在是我生命中唯一正常的人了
Cecile is the only thing... normal I have in my life right now,
我想要拥有正常的生活
and I like having something normal.
我要是告诉了她这些
If I tell her about all this...
就不会正常了
that goes away.
但你如果不告诉她
But if you don't tell her...
就不存在"我们"了
There may not be an "us."
乔  没有所谓正常的事物
Joe, there's no such thing as normal.
爱是唯一值得去奋斗的目标
Love is the only thing that makes the fight worth it,
也是唯一能让我们坚持下去的动力
and it's the only thing that's gonna get us through it.
各位  你们在这啊
Guys. Guys, there you are.
我们有了大麻烦
We got a big problem.
特蕾西不见了
Tracy's gone.
我找过了中城大学  她家  吉特斯咖啡店
I checked CCU, her apartment, and Jitter's.
都找不到特蕾西
Tracy's not in any of them.
我敢说我们说话这会儿
I'll bet you Savitar and Killer Frost
萨维塔和冰霜杀手正在追杀她
are hunting her down as we speak.
HR  你是最后和特蕾西见过的人
H.R., you were with Tracy last.
-她当时怎么样  -很慌乱  韦斯特小姐
- How did she seem? - Rattled, Miss West.
很慌乱  但我对她说了些激励和安慰的话
Rattled, but I gave her a rousing and reassuring pep talk,
-她应该没事的  -所以她才离开了
- so I think she's okay. - Oh, that's why she left.
不是因为这个  好吧  告诉你们好了
That's not why--  look, I will have you know
我有本讲励志演讲的书
my book on motivational speeches,
《结果好  一切都好》
"All's Wells that Ends Wells"--
-特蕾西有危险  -没错
- Tracy is in danger. - You're right.
-爱瑞丝  专注点  -什么
- Iris! Focus! - What?
-我们现在得找到她  -对  得找到她
- We need to find her. Now. - Yeah, we gotta find her.
她还能在哪
Where else could she be?
我们不如从她的未来全息图开始找吧
Why don't we start with her future hologram, right?
这会给我们一些启发
That's--  that would give us insight
-了解她的精神状态  对吧  -没错
- into her psyche, no? - Of course, yeah.
-真不错  -谢谢
- That's pretty good. - Thank you.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
-她真可爱  -这真诡异
- She's cute. - This is creepy, right?
对  我觉得她还挺迷人
Yeah. I find her charming.
你觉得全息图可以截屏吗
Do you think you could screenshot a hologram?
回看上一张
Go back to that last one.
对  还有一张很像这张
Yeah, there's another one like it.
-看那里  放大  -好
- Look at that. Zoom in. - Yeah.
[拉丁语]
Eppur si...
Eppur si muove.
特蕾西  你真是科学的小情人
Tracy, you blessed paramour of science.
大伙  我知道她在哪里了
Gang, I know exactly where she is.
[拉丁语]
Eppur si muove.
"然而它会继续运动下去"
"And yet it moves."
伽利略的一句名言
Galileo's famous statement uttered moments
在他被迫收回地球绕着太阳转的理论
after being forced to recant his theory that the Earth
之后说的
revolves around the sun.
然而它会继续运动下去
"And yet it moves."
我的闪电侠摩卡
Mocha Flash for me.
给女士的极速咖啡
A Zoom for milady.
谢谢
Thank you.
你太客气了
You're very welcome.
你怎么知道我在这里
How did you know I was here?
我好像有一些全息的追踪线索
I might have done a bit of holographic stalktag.
我用全息图追踪了你
I stalked you holographically.
你是说  在未来
You mean, in the future,
我依然喜欢这位五百岁的意大利博学家
I'm still obsessed with a 500-year-old Italian polymath?
是的  就是这样
Yes, it would appear so.
-对不起我跑掉了  我只是  -没事
- I'm sorry I ran off. I just... - No.
-我需要冷静一下  -当然
- Just needed to clear my head - Of course.
思考...  这里是我最喜欢那样做的地方
and think and... this is where I do it best.
我能看出来
Well, I can see that.
这真是座启发人的雕像
That statue is nothing if not inspiring.
浓密的胡子  先知一般  智慧
Concrete beard, foreboding, smart.
-非常启发人  -没错
- Totally inspiring. - Yup.
你知道吗
You know
伽利略那个时代的人也觉得他是个疯子
Galileo's peers thought he was a crackpot too.
-是那样吗  -没错
- Is that right? - Yeah.
我以前觉得那样安心
And I used to find that comforting.
但当你的队员
But then when your team
告诉我未来的样子
showed me the future
告诉我我那些疯狂的想法
and showed me that my crazy ideas
其实并不疯狂
aren't so crazy after all,
我却感受到了前所未有的恐惧
I just felt more intimidated than ever.
我能看出来
Well, I can see that.
就像是你一直坐在伟人的阴影下
It's like you're sitting in the shadow of greatness.
-你自己的伟大  对吗  -就是这样
- Your own greatness, right? - Exactly!
我已经失败了无数次
It's like I've failed so many times.
那是我擅长做的事
That's all I know how to do.
但我不知道要如何...
I don't know how to be that...
做一个全息图里那样杰出的女人
brilliant woman in the hologram.
不过你不会懂的
But you wouldn't understand.
你是个天才
You are a born genius.
关于那个
Yeah, about that.
我其实不算是个天才
I'm not... technically a genius.
那不太光彩  我很抱歉让你误解
That was a cheap thing to do. I'm sorry I misled you
我是个天才
about me being a genius.
重点是  你...
The point is, you...
才是个天才
are...a genius.
你是的  我知道  我能
You are. I know it. I can--
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
就在那里  就在那里
It's right there. It's right there,
就藏在表面之下
just brimming just below the surface.
-是吗  -当然
- It is? - Yes, absolutely!
是的  特蕾西
Yes, it is, Tracy.
你能打败萨维塔
And you can defeat Savitar.
你只需要相信自己
All you need is to just believe in yourself.
不管怎样...
And for what it's worth...
我对你有信心
I already do.
-我不知道你会过来  -好吧
- I didn't know you were dropping by. - Yeah, well,
如果你看了我发的短信  你就知道了
if you had read any of my texts, you'd know.
这样啊
Yeah.
-对不起  -我知道
- I'm sorry. - I know.
那就是我来的原因  我...
It's why I'm here. Look, I--
即使是普通人也能看出
You know, it doesn't take a detective to see
有些事不太对
that something's not right.
塞西尔
Look, Cecile--
是因为我今早说了"我爱你"吗
Is it because I said, "I love you", this morning?
因为  乔  这没关系的
Because, Joe, it's--it's okay
如果你还没准备好回应我
if you're not ready to say it back.
不  和那个没有关系
No, no. It's not about that.
没关系  那是怎么了
No? Well, then what's going on?
你今天一天都很奇怪
'Cause you've been acting weird all day.
不只是今早我们在一起的时候
I mean, not just with us this morning
在单位说到那个超能力者的时候也是
but at work with that meta case.
你得跟我说说  乔
You gotta give me something, Joe.
我只能告诉你...
All I can say is...
我有一部分生活非常复杂
that part of my life is very complicated.
如果你要成为那其中的一部分
And if you were to become part of that,
你的生活也会变得很复杂
your life would be very complicated,
这会改变我们
and it would change us.
而这种改变是永久的
And I mean change us forever.
这没什么不好
That's not a bad thing, you know.
也算是成长
It's called growth.
我在想
And then I was thinking about...
今天早上
what you said
你说的话
this morning, and
告诉了我你现在的状态
it told me where you were.
也显现出了我的状态
It also showed me where I was, and...
使得局面更加复杂了
and you add those complications,and
我觉得我们不应该再见面了
I think we should stop seeing each other.
真的吗
Really?
你觉得我们应该这么做吗
That's what you think we should do?
我觉得这对我们来说都是最好的
I-I-I think it's the best thing for both of us.
我以为我们在一起
Here I was, thinking that being together
才是对我们来说最好的
was the best thing for both of us.
我还是
I guess I'll...
我们警局见  乔
I'll see you around the station, Joe.
-塞西尔  -乔
- Cecile! - Joe!
-别想  我肯定比你快  -乔
- No! Guarantee you I'm faster. - Joe!
凯特琳
Caitlin...
我们可以好好聊聊
we can talk about this.
是我说  你听着
I'll talk. You listen.
一小时后  你会收到一个地址
In an hour, you're gonna get a message with an address.
把特蕾西·布兰德带给我  不然我就杀了她
Bring me Tracy Brand, or I will kill your little sweetheart.
乔
Joe.
慢着
Wait!
所以你是说如果我们不把特蕾西交给冰霜杀手
So you're saying that if we don't turn Tracy over to Killer Frost...
她就会杀了塞西尔
She's gonna kill Cecile.
如果我说的没错的话
Correct me if I'm wrong, but Tracy is our key
特蕾西是我们找到萨维塔的关键  对吗
to finding Savitar, right?
没错  但是我们又能怎么办呢
Yes, but what are we gonna do?
让冰霜杀手名副其实
We gonna just let Killer Frost
真的去杀人吗
live up to her name and kill somebody?
当然不行  除非我先答应
Not if I have anything to say about it.
我所说的是
All I'm saying is,
我们无论付出什么代价都要救她
we need to do whatever it takes to save her.
没有人会死  好吗
No one's gonna die, all right?
我保证  我们会把她救回来
We're gonna get her back. I promise.
是他们
That's them.
他们在老德莱斯勒工厂
They're at the Old Dressler Factory.
我们知道他们的位置  这很重要
Okay, we know where they are. That's something.
我们该怎么做
So what do we do?
我有个计划
I have a plan.
西斯科  我们能聊聊吗
Cisco, can I have a quick word?
现在不行  朱利安
Not now, Julian.
拜托你听我说  伙计
Listen, please, mate.
听我说完
Just--just hear me out.
我知道你害怕失去她
I know you're terrified of losing her.
我也一样
So am I.
我也知道
I know you're--you're
你担心没法控制你的超能力
worried about not being able to control your powers,
但是我知道你可以
but I know you can.
我认为你的能力
I don't think your abilities have ever come from a place
并不来自于负面情绪或是某种恨意
of--of negativity or--or hate.
而是来自美好的地方
They come from somewhere good.
你的超能力是源于爱
They come from love.
如果你能在你内心找到爱
And if you can find it in you to stop her,then
那我觉得我们能拯救她
I really think we can save her.
回见  伙计
Cheers, mate.
你记得我说过的
Yeah, you know how I said, you know,
我们会保护你吗
we were gonna keep you safe?
记得
Yeah.
可是  现在我得让你帮忙做件危险的事
So, um, now I need to ask you to do something dangerous.
塞西尔
Cecile!
你还好吗
Are you all right?
乔  我没事  她没伤害我
Joe! I'm okay. She didn't hurt me.
那是因为杀了你  对我一点好处也没有
That's because killing you... does nothing for me.
而杀了你  特蕾西  那就另当别论了
Killing you, Tracy? That's everything.
把她交出来
Hand her over.
你没必要这么做
You don't have to do this.
有必要
Yes, I do.
为什么
Why?
因为萨维塔下令了吗
Because Savitar commands it?
他又不是神
He's not a god.
他只是利用你的人
He's just a man that's using you.
-拜托  我们是自己人  -自己人
- Come on, you're one of us. - One of us?
-我们是家人  -我们是家人
- We're family. - We're family?
我们到死都会保护彼此
We protect each other till the end.
你怎么知道这些话
How are you doing that?
萨维塔跟我说了你会说的话
Savitar told me everything you'd say.
你俩比你以为的还要像
You two are more alike than you realize.
所以萨维塔才知道
You see, that's how Savitar knows every move
你的一举一动
you're going to make.
他总是抢先你一步
He's always one step ahead of you,
因为对他来说这全是旧事重演
because this is all history to him.
所以我才知道西斯科现在在椽子上
That's how I know Cisco's in the rafters right now.
不
Oh, no.
到此为止  凯特琳
It's over, Caitlin.
凯特琳死了
Caitlin is dead.
我不觉得
Not to me.
走走走
Go. Go. Go. Go.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
你还活着
You're alive.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我得让你停手才能救你
I had to stop you to save you.
我差一点就飞升了  闪电侠
My ascension is nearly at hand, Flash.
等我飞升  你就会堕落
As I rise, you will fall.
我们是怎么不断从这些事中活下来的
How do we keep surviving these things?
因为我们掌握着自己的命运
Because we're in control of our fates.
她怎么知道我在椽子上面
And how did she know I was up in the rafters?
她现在也能通灵了吗
Is she psychic now too?
还有你俩同时
And that thing where you guys were talking
说出一句话  你觉得她怎么做到的
at the same time? How do you think she was doing that?
不知道  她说萨维塔告诉她会发生什么
I don't know. She said Savitar told her what was gonna happen.
不可能  这不只是预知未来
No way, man. This wasn't just brushing up on days to come.
这简直一字不差
This was precise.
瘆人的一字不差
Scary precise.
就像萨维塔也在场
Like Savitar was there.
我不懂的是萨维塔出现时
What I don't understand is why Savitar
为何不杀了特蕾西
wouldn't kill Tracy when he showed up.
我是说他为何选择救凯特琳
I mean, why would he choose to rescue Caitlin?
他还有事要她帮忙
He needs her for something.
我们得搞清是什么事
We gotta figure out what that is.
同意
Agreed.
多亏了西斯科  我们拿到她完全
Thanks to Cisco, we now have a sample of her blood
突变成冰霜杀手后的血液样本
when she was fully mutated as Killer Frost.
这个  可能是制造
This? It could be the key
逆向解药的关键  所以
to reverse engineering a cure, so...
干得漂亮  朋友
it's good work, mate.
你也是
You too.
你在这啊
Oh, there you are.
我给咱们准备了些咖啡
I brought us some coffee treats.
可惜我们的辣椒粉用完了
Unfortunately, we were all out of cayenne.
小心  很烫
Careful, that's hot.
对啊  很烫  抱歉
Yeah, hot, hot, sorry.
-你怎么样  -小心
- How are you? Oh! Ha! Whoo! - Careful.
你还好吗
How are you holding up?
太烫了
Whew, it's hot.
我还在消化
Well, I'm processing.
那真是  我是说那声音
That was really-- I mean, the voice...
"嗡"的一声
And the "Whoom!"
冰霜杀手  萨维塔
Killer Frost? Savitar?
你知道有些人的名字真的很吓人
You know some people with really scary names.
太难以接受了吗
Eh, but is it too much?
这里所有人都会理解的
All of us here would understand.
对我个人来说  我只想确保
Personally, I just-- I just wanna make sure that,
你不会受伤
you know, you don't get hurt.
其实  我在想
As a matter of fact, I was thinking--
-我也在想  -是吗
- I was thinking too. - Yeah?
在想萨维塔
About Savitar.
他的战衣反射光的方式
The way the light reflects off his suit,
跟我见过的所有金属化合物都不同
it's unlike any other metallic compound I have ever seen.
我和你想的不是一回事
Hmm, you and I were thinking about different things.
你觉得那是什么
What do you think it is?
根据费米液体理论  任何非费米液体
In Fermi liquid theory, any sort of non-Fermi liquid
都被称为"奇异金属"
is called "Strange metal."
那是种能在高温时分散热量的
It's a theoretical compound capable of dispersing heat
理论性化合物  我觉得萨维塔速度太快了
at high temperatures. I think Savitar travels so fast
因此他需要那件战衣来中和
that he needs that suit to neutralize the charge
身体周围形成的电荷
he builds up around him.
有意思  那如果没了战衣
Huh. Interesting. So without the suit,
那他只是个被强大静电困住的家伙
he's just a dude with a bad case of static cling.
对  如果我们可以造出
Yeah. So if we could build a device
能控制那股超能力的装备
capable of harnessing that power,
理论上讲  就能用他的速度对付他
theoretically, we could use his own velocity against him.
并把他困在神速力里
And trap him in the Speed Force.
特蕾西  你真是个天才
Tracy, you are indeed a genius.
-还差一点  -对  快了
- I'm getting there. - Well, yes, you are.
就是说你会留下来帮我们
That means you're gonna stay and help us.
是这意思吗
Is that what that means?
如果我留下  那就意味着未来改变了
If I do, does that mean the future's changing?
我想那意味着我的未来肯定变了
I think it means mine certainly has.
感谢你来见我  请进
Thanks for seeing me. Come on in.
你还好吗
So how are you doing?
乔  我没事  只是
Joe, I'm fine. I just--
真希望你能跟我说
you know, I wish that you would've told me
你这是怎么了
what was going on with you.
虽然我现在显然也知道了一些
Although I...obviously have some idea now.
你被牵扯进来都怪我
It was my fault that you got caught up in all this.
很抱歉  塞西尔
I'm so sorry, Cecile.
乔  我也是  听着  我
Joe, me too. Look, I--
今早你跟我说爱我的时候
When you told me that you loved me this morning...
-我沉默了  -是啊
- I froze. - Yeah.
我知道那意味着我们的关系
I knew that it meant that we moved up a level
达到新高度
in our relationship.
而对我来说
And...for me,
那样会带来很多负担
that level comes with a lot of baggage.
比如冰霜杀手和闪电侠
Like Killer Frost and The Flash?
对
Yeah.
所以你觉得拒绝我是正确的
So you thought that pushing me away was the thing to do?
我以为那是在保护你
I thought that I was protecting you.
显然我错了
Clearly I was wrong,
因为我不仅骗了你
because not only did I lie to you.
也骗了自己
I lied to myself.
你知道吗
And you know what?
我受够了
I'm done with that.
我受够这个了
And I'm done with this.
谢谢你并没有特别介意我还戴着这个
Thank you for not making a big deal about me wearing this.
塞西尔·霍尔顿
Cecile Horton...
我爱你
I love you.
我的心里只有你
I love you with all my heart.
我很抱歉没有对你坦诚
And I'm sorry that I was dishonest with you.
从现在起
And from now on,
我们间不会再有秘密
there will be no secrets between us.
好
Okay.
我早就该告诉你的
I should have told you a long time ago.
但也没什么
But it's not bad.
-沃利  -爸爸
- Wally! - Hey, Dad.
怎么样
How was it?
很好啊  杰西向你问好
It was--yeah, it was great. Jesse says hi.
-你跟塞西尔聊了吗  -聊了
- So you talked to Cecile? - I did.
全告诉她了
Told her everything.
告诉她我爱她
Told her I love her.
我告诉她你就是闪电侠
I told her that you were The Flash
沃利就是闪电小子
and that Wally was Kid Flash.
别担心  她向我保证
Don't worry. She promised me...
她不会告诉琼妮
that she wouldn't tell Joanie.
什么让你改变心意了
What changed your mind?
你  你们大家
You. All of you.
爱是我们在这个世界上唯一拥有的东西
I mean, love's the only thing we got in this world.
没有爱  什么都不重要了
Without it, nothing really matters.
如果没有爱  谁知道我们会变成什么样子
And who knows what we'd become if we didn't have it?
-地球三怎么样  -挺好的
- How was Earth-3? - Yeah, um,
和杰西在一起感觉特别好
hanging out with Jesse was awesome.
爱是我们在这个世界上唯一拥有的东西
I mean, love's the only thing we got in this world.
没有爱  什么都不重要了
Without it, nothing really matters.
如果没有爱  谁知道我们会变成什么样子
And who knows what we'd become if we didn't have it?
你把我害成这样  巴里
You did this to me, Barry.
-我创造了你  -我创造了自己
- I created you? - I created myself.
你甚至会自己创造时间残余
You're even gonna create time remnants of yourself,
但他会把他们都杀了
but he's gonna kill them all.
萨维塔跟我说了你会说的话
Savitar told me everything you'd say.
你俩比你以为的还要像
You two are more alike than you realize.
萨维塔知道你的一举一动
Savitar knows every move you're going to make.
他总是抢先你一步
He's always one step ahead of you.
这全是旧事重演
This is all history.
这不只是预知未来
This wasn't just brushing up on days to come.
这简直一字不差
This was precise.
就像萨维塔也在场
Like Savitar was there.
如果没有爱  谁知道我们会变成什么样子
Who knows what we'd become if we didn't have it?
抢先你一步
One step ahead of you.
旧事重演
All history.
我就是未来的闪电侠
I am the future Flash.
抢先你一步
One step ahead of you.
巴里
Barry!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
抱歉
Uh, I'm sorry.
我一会儿就回  好吗
I'll be--I'll be right back, all right?
我在这里
I'm here!
我知道你是谁了
I know who you are.
时间问题
It's about time.
是的  没错
Yes, it is.
你的一切都和时间有关  不是吗
Everything with you is about time, isn't it?
过去  现在  将来...
The past, the present, the future--
你全都知道  对吗
you know all of it, right?
你知道我的一切
And you know everything about me!
还有乔
About Joe!
还有沃利
About Wally.
还有爱瑞丝
And Iris!
你知道我们的力量  我们的恐惧
You know our strengths. You know our fears.
你知道我们有多爱彼此
You how much we love each other.
你知道怎么利用这份爱对付我们
And you know how to use that love against us.
一直以来  我们都觉得无法阻止你
All this time, we thought that we couldn't stop you,
因为你快我们一步  但并非如此
because you're one step ahead, but that's not it.
你不仅仅知道我们会发生什么
You don't just know what's gonna happen to us.
你在场  你已经经历过了
You were there. You've lived it.
你记得当你还是我的时候所发生的一切
You remembered, when you were me.
我从一开始就是这么告诉你的
Like I told you from the beginning,
我就是未来的闪电侠
I am the future Flash.